{
    "id": "962a5730ee5440a583d5c3e340a942b6",
    "title": "Gap Filling Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "You must be ashamed …………………………",
            "description": "Ashamed is used with of. Also when both the subject and the object refer to the same person, we use the reflexive pronoun.",
            "answers": [
                "with yourself",
                "of you",
                "of yourself"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was at university, I ……………………….. play tennis every evening.",
            "description": "We use used to to talk about past habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "was used to",
                "use to",
                "used to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She was so frightened ……………………….. she could not even move.",
            "description": "The conjunction so...that... expresses cause and effect. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "for",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………….. had she finished one project before she started working on the next.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Hardly",
                "As soon as",
                "No sooner"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………… he was suffering from some health problems, the doctor advised him to take a break.",
            "description": "As gives the reason for something. ",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Though",
                "For"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the watch ………………………. he bought for me.",
            "description": "Either that or which can refer to things in identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me …………………….. I had seen his purse.",
            "description": "Either if or whether can be used to introduce an yes/no question.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "whether",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Hindi as well as Marathi …………………….. spoken in Mumbai.",
            "description": "When we connect two singular subjects with as well as, the verb is singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "is",
                "am"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I have been living in Kerala …………………………. 5 years.",
            "description": "Use for to indicate duration. ",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "since",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I didn’t go ………………………… I hadn’t been invited.",
            "description": "Because gives the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "so",
                "because of"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. fast, the cops caught the thief.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Ran",
                "Running",
                "Having run"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had invited her, she ....................................",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will come",
                "would come",
                "would have come"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}